Finding Aid for Harry H. Bandholtz Papers, 1890-1937 (Microfilm Edition)
Bentley Historical Library
Harry H. Bandholtz Papers (Microform)
1890-1937
1899-1925
Bentley Historical Library
Bandholtz, Harry Hill, 1864-1925
9436 mf 255
12 microfilms
1 maps
2 oversize folders
10 folders
Career military officer, served in the Philippines ca. 1900-1913, chief of the Philippine Constabulary, 1907-1913; papers include correspondence, constabulary reports, diaries, topical files, visual materials, and scrapbooks.
The collection came to the library in three accessions, the first in 1965 from Grafton Cook who had purchased the papers from Mrs. Bandholtz. (Donor no. 4271 ) The second in 1994 came from the estate of Mary M. Connelly, a friend of Mrs. Bandholtz. (Donor no. 8258 ). A small additional accession was received from Grafton Cook (Donor no. 4271 ) in 2005
The collection is open for research.
The originals of the Bandholtz papers are held by the Bentley Historical Library. Researchers will normally be expected to use the microfilm edition.
Harry Hill Bandholtz, a lifelong military man, was born in Constantine, Michigan on December 18, 1864. He graduated from the United States Military Academy at West Point in 1890, and then for the next thirty-three years he served his country in more than a dozen different assignments and posts. Bandholtz early demonstrated his competence as an officer with leadership abilities, and he was continuously rewarded with a steady series of promotions to different challenging assignments. He was a front-line officer, a teacher of the military arts, an administrator within the military hierarchy, and a skilled and respected diplomat.
Following some early assignments, Bandholtz in 1896 was selected to teach military science and tactics at Michigan Agricultural College (now Michigan State University). He was a teacher for two years when, with the outbreak of war with Spain in 1898, he returned to active duty. In Cuba he served in the Santiago campaign with the 7th U.S. Infantry, receiving a Silver Star citation for his participation. Between 1898 and 1900, he held different positions in the United States and Cuba. In July 1900, he left Cuba for the Philippine Islands where he served for the next thirteen years. Bandholtz' first responsibility was to help establish peace in the Islands which was then being disturbed by various local insurgent armies, notably in Central Luzon and on the Island of Marinduque and in Tayabas Province.
Bandholtz quickly earned the respect of the Philippine people. In 1902, he was elected governor of Tayabas Province, the only regular army officer to be elected to so high a position. In 1903, he was appointed assistant chief of Philippine Constabulary with the temporary rank of colonel and placed in command of the District of Southern Luzon. Bandholtz was an effective commander who arranged for the unconditional surrender of insurgent general Simeon Ola and his forces in Albay. In 1905, he was transferred to the District of Central Luzon where he similarly apprehended Philippine bandit leaders. In 1907, he was appointed chief of Philippine Constabulary with the temporary rank of brigadier general. He held this position until relieved on September 1, 1913.
Upon returning to the United States, Bandholtz was put in command of Fort Porter at Buffalo, New York (1914-1915) and a battalion of the 30th Infantry at Plattsburg Barracks, N.Y. (1915-1916). With this command, he served on the Mexican border for six months in 1916. During World War I, Bandholtz served on the Western Front, receiving promotion to brigadier general with command of the 58th Infantry Brigade of the 29th Division. In September 1918, General Pershing appointed Bandholtz to be provost marshal general of the American Expeditionary Forces where his duties included reorganizing the military police corps and managing the guarding of German prisoners of war.
From August 1919 to February 1920, Bandholtz served as American representative on the Interallied Military Mission sent to Hungary by the Supreme Council to control the unauthorized Rumanian occupation of that country. Bandholtz later served as the first United States Commissioner to Hungary. He returned to the United States in 1920, receiving promotion to permanent brigadier general with command of the 13th Infantry Brigade at Camps Funston and Meade. In August 1921, Bandholtz was assigned the duty of organizing and commanding the newly authorized District of Washington. Shortly thereafter, he was sent to West Virginia when the state authorities requested federal aid in maintaining the peace during a strike of coal miners. Bandholtz retired from military service in 1923 with the rank of major general. He died in his hometown of Constantine, May 7, 1925.
The Bandholtz collection, covering the period of ca. 1890 to 1925 (with some later papers of his wife Inez Bandholtz), consists mainly of materials accumulated while Bandholtz was stationed in the Philippines, 1900-1913. Except for this time in the Far East, Bandholtz was always on the move with ever changing assignments, and consequently his files covering his work on the Mexican border, for example, or in the West Virginia coal miners strike are substantially thinner. But in the Philippines, because he was a provincial governor and head of the indigenous military force, Bandholtz was at the center of affairs in this period of Philippine history. And beyond that, he made an effort to maintain and preserve as much documentation from his service here as he could.
The Bandholtz papers came to the library in three separate accessions in 1965, 1994 and 2005. The first accession includes the following series: Correspondence (1899-1913), Invitations, Miscellaneous, Published Materials, and Philippine Constabulary Reports (1906-1913). The second accession includes the following series: Biographical-Personal, Correspondence (1895-1925), Diaries (1900-1923), Topical Files, Visual Materials, Scrapbooks, and Inez Bandholtz papers. Although there is some overlap (especially in the two Correspondence series), the two accessions have been kept separate, and not interfiled, so that researchers who examined the first accession might read from the new material without having to go through the entire collection. This encoded finding aid treats the correspondence as a single series although it has not been interfiled. the third accession consists of correspondence (1903-1912), chiefly confidential letters between Bandholtz and Luke Wright and Leonard Wood, concerning major military an political issues in the Philippines.
Freemasonry -- Michigan.; Hungary -- History -- Revolution, 1918-1919.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Philippines -- Foreign relations -- Japan.; Postage-stamps.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1908.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1912.; Tariff -- United States.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Japan.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1909.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1909-1913.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1897-1901.; World War, 1914-1918.; Spanish-American War, 1898.; Budapest (Hungary); Constantine (Mich.); Dwellings -- Michigan -- Constantine.; Military officers.; Military art and science.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Philippines -- History -- Philippine American War, 1899-1902.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; World War, 1914-1918 -- France.; Drawings.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Aguinaldo, Emilio, 1869-1964.; Bandholtz, Harry Hill, 1864-1925.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Inter-allied Military Mission to Hungary, 1919-1920.; Malcolm, George A. (George Arthur), 1881-1961.; Osmeña, Sergio, 1878-1961.; Progressive Party (1912); Quezon, Manuel Luis, 1878-1944.; Republican Party (Mich.); Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; United States. Army.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Military Affairs.; United Spanish War Veterans.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Bandholtz, Harry Hill, 1864-1925.; Geronimo, Apache chief, 1829-1909.; Philippine Constabulary.; United States Military Academy. Class of 1890.; Allen, Henry T. (Henry Tureman), 1859-1930.; Bell, James Franklin, 1856-1919.; Bigelow, Poultney, 1855-; Bliss, Tasker Howard, 1853-1930.; Bumpus, Hermon Carey, 1862-1943.; Burrows, Julius C. (Julius Caesar), 1837-1915.; Carpenter, Frank W. (Frank Watson), 1871-1938.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Forbes, W. Cameron (William Cameron), 1870-1959.; Funston, Frederick, 1865-1917.; Geronimo, Apache chief, 1829-1909.; Gilbert, Newton W. (Newton Whiting), 1862-1939.; Harbord, James G. (James Guthrie), 1866-1947.; Hersey, Mark Leslie, 1863-1934.; Ide, Henry Clay, 1844-1921.; Kahn, Julius, 1861-1924.; McIntyre, Frank, 1865-1944.; Mills, Albert Leopold, 1854-1916.; Pershing, John J. (John Joseph), 1860-1948.; Polk, Frank L. (Frank Lyon), 1871-1943.; Rivers, William Cannon, 1866-1943.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Smith, James Francis, 1859-1928.; Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958.; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.; Wright, Luke E., 1846-1922.
- Correspondence, 1895-1925; 2.8 linear feet
  The Correspondence series (1895-1925; 2.8 linear feet) is significant for those exchanges with individuals (American and Filipino) important to Philippine history in the period after the 1898 war. This correspondence came to the library in two accessions. There is a selective index to the significant correspondents in each accession Additional Descriptive Data section of this finding aid.
  - 1899-April 10, 1907
    - 1899-April 10, 1907 (Reel 1)
    - April 11, 1907-May 10, 1909 (Reel 2)
    - May 11, 1909-September 1910 (Reel 3)
    - October 1910-December 15, 1911 (Reel 4)
    - December 16, 1911-June 1913 (Reel 5)
    - Undated (Reel 5)
  - 1895-1925
    (received after the first accession of Bandholtz papers)
    Correspondence (1895-1925; .5 linear feet) includes messages exchanged with Bandholtz' friends and colleagues. Like the correspondence in the first accession, this file relates mainly to his lengthy service in the Philippines. Much of the post-1913 correspondence consists of "staying in touch" letters or relates to personal matters such as his stamp collection.
    - Undated (Reel 7)
    - 1895-1922 (Reel 7)
    - 1923-1925 (Reel 7)
  - By name (Reel 8)
    A portion of the correspondence received in the second accession of Bandholtz papers was organized by correspondent, including Manuel Quezon, W. C. Rives, Herbert B. Swope and Leonard Wood.
    - Quezon, Manuel (Reel 8)
    - Rives, W.C (Reel 8)
    - Swope, Herbert B (Reel 8)
    - Wood, Leonard (Reel 8)
- Invitations
  - 1906-1913 (Reel 5)
- Miscellaneous
  - Flyers, programs, etc (Reel 5)
- Published Material
  - 1911-1919, 3 folders (Reel 5)
- Philippine Constabulary Reports, 1906-1913; 4 volumes
  Philippine Constabulary Reports (1906-1913; 4 volumes). The volumes, although labeled Philippine Constabulary Reports, actually include different kinds of records, some collected by Bandholtz rather than created by him. Volume 1 (dated 1906-1909) in fact dates back to 1898 and consists entirely of reports and memoranda concerning the Japan-Philippine Island relationship. Groupings of documents within this volume bear the title "Compilation of Papers on Japanese Propagandism." There is a partial index to the contents of this volume at the end. Volume 2 (1910), Volume 3 (1911), and Volume 4 (1912-June 1913) continue the memoranda and reports of the first volume and the theme of Japanese involvement in the Philippines.
  - 1906-June 1913 (Reel 6)
- Biographical Material/personal
  - Biographical sketches, service record, clippings, etc (Reel 7)
    (see also citation in UAm oversize folder)
  - Family Miscellanea (including earlier letters from family members) (Reel 7)
  - Address books (Reel 7)
  - Speeches (Reel 7)
- Diaries, 1900-1923; 23 volumes
  Diaries (1900-1923; 23 volumes) contains Bandholtz' often detailed comments on his life as a career officer. The diaries are small and usually written in pencil.
  - 1900-1911 (Reel 8)
  - 1912-1923 (Reel 9)
- Topical Files, 1890-1925; 0.5 linear feet
  Topical Files (1890-1925; .5 linear feet) consists of subject-related material on such topics as Bandholtz' investment in the Polillo Land Company, the West Virginia coal miners strike of 1921, and his interest in the Hungary Society of America. This series also contains income tax returns and his service orders. The earliest item is a course notebook, ca. 1890, when Bandholtz attended West Point Military Academy.
  - American Expeditionary Force, Provost Marshal General, 1918-1919 (Reel 9)
  - Bandholtz, May (hospitalization), 1920-1921 (Reel 9)
  - Bandholtz, May (HHB divorce from), 1921 (Reel 9)
  - Hungary miscellaneous (Reel 9)
  - Hungary Society of America (Reel 9)
  - Income tax files and related (Reel 9)
  - Interallied Military Mission to Hungary, 1919
    - General (Reel 9)
    - Draft of Undiplomatic Diary; also excerpts from official report (Reel 9)
    - Memoranda, reports, and other documents regarding Hungarians held as prisoners of war by Roumanians, 1919 (Reel 10)
  - Invitations (from emperor of Japan and others) (Reel 10)
  - Masonic miscellaneous (Reel 10)
  - Philippines
    - Volume containing carbon copies of orders given by HHB, 1900-1901 (Reel 10)
    - Miscellaneous documents containing Bandholtz references (Reel 10)
    - Miscellaneous documents (in Spanish) (Reel 10)
    - Miscellanea (Reel 10)
  - Polillo Land Company, 1904-1907 (Reel 10)
    (see also map cataloged and stored with map collection)
  - Service orders, etc (Reel 10)
  - Taylor (Wallace) appointment materials, 1914 (Reel 10)
  - Travel: Memoranda of trip from Manila to Java (author unknown), 1911 (Reel 10)
  - War Department, Headquarters District of Washington (orders, memoranda, etc.), 1921-1922 (Reel 10)
  - West Point notebook, circa 1890 (Reel 10)
    (also class of 1890 program and Christmas cards)
  - West Virginia Coal strike, 1921 (Reel 10)
  - Willard, C.E. (correspondence with family member in jail) (Reel 10)
  - Worcester, Dean C., 1913 (Reel 10)
    (file regarding Worcester's "A Report on Slavery and Peonage in the Philippines")
- Visual Materials, 1.3 linear feet, 2 oversize folders
  Visual Materials (1890-1925 and 1937; 1.3 linear feet and 2 oversize folders) is a series that more thoroughly covers Bandholtz's career. It ranges from a sketchbook (ca. 1890) of drawings of his and his West Point classmates (including a drawing done by Geronimo in 1893) to extensive photographs (loose and in albums) relating to the work of the Philippine Constabulary (including the capture of different insurgent leaders). This series includes other photos from the period of his service in France during World War I and in Hungary with the Interallied Mission to Hungary, 1919-1920. Other photographs of interest are interior views of Bandholtz' Constantine, Michigan, home. The series also contains a photograph album, 1937, of the dedication of the Harry Hill Bandholtz statue in Budapest, Hungary.
  - Drawings
    - West Point sketchbook containing drawings of HHB's West Point classmates, circa 1890 (Reel 10)
      (volume includes a loose drawing, perhaps of HHB, drawn and signed by Geronimo while in custody at Mt. Vernon Barracks, Alabama, 1893)
  - Photographs
    - Portraits (include photograph of HHB statue in Budapest) (Reel 10)
      (see also oversize folder, UAl)
    - Philippine views, 1901; undated (Reel 11)
    - Philippine Constabulary, circa 1900-1905 (Reel 11)
      (see also oversize folder UAm)
    - Constantine (Michigan) home (also family (?) members) (Reel 11)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Reel 11)
  - Photograph albums
    - circa 1903 (Reel 11)
      (Philippine views, Philippine Constabulary, Manila)
    - circa 1900-1920 (Reel 11)
      (Philippine views, Constantine, Michigan, 29th Infantry at Plattsburg, 1914, military life, 1914-1920)
    - 1898-1923 (Reel 11)
      (Inez Bandholtz, portraits, military figures, Constantine, Michigan, home)
    - 1918-1919 (Reel 11)
      (France and the Western Front, Interallied Mission to Hungary, Hungary and Budapest views)
    - circa 1910 (Reel 11)
      (China, Japan, informal photos of various acquaintances and friends)
    - 1937 (Reel 11)
      (HHB statue dedication in Budapest, Hungary)
- Scrapbooks, 1890s-1925; 0.5 linear feet
  Scrapbooks (1890s-1925; .5 linear feet) contain newspaper coverage of HHB's career.
  - 1896-1909 (Reel 11)
  - 1901-1918 (Reel 11)
    (clippings not filed chronologically)
  - 1919-1924 (Reel 11)
    (loose pages; probably Inez Bandholtz's scrapbook)
  - 1890s-1910 (Reel 11)
    (scrapbook maintained by HHB's mother and relating to his career)
  - Newspaper clippings (Reel 11)
- Inez Bandholtz, 1924-1937; 0.3 linear feet
  Inez Bandholtz (1924-1937; .3 linear feet) consists of one letter from Bandholtz to his wife, letters regarding his estate and the sale of his stamp collection, and files relating to the Bandholtz statue in Budapest and Inez Bandholtz' visit to Hungary.
  - Letters of condolence, 1925 (Reel 11)
  - Sale of HHB stamp collection, 1925 (Reel 12)
  - Visit to Hungary for the dedication of the HHB statue, 1937 (Reel 12)
  - Correspondence with, and relating to, Col. Eugen Boross, 1936-1941 (Reel 12)
  - Harry Howland/Haan brothers correspondence, 1925-1931 (Reel 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1924-1937 (Reel 12)
    (including letter from HHB, 1924)
  - Diary, 1936 (Reel 12)
- Correspondence and Miscellanea, 1903-1912
  Correspondence (1903-1912, 0.2 linear ft.), chiefly confidential letters between Bandholtz and Luke Wright and Leonard Wood, concerns major political and military issues in the Philippines. A copy of J. G. Harbord's 1911 report on the Philippine Constabulary is also included. This material, received in the 2005 accession, has not been microfilmed.
  - 1903-1912 (Box 8)
  - Miscellanea (Box 8)
Selective index to correspondents in 1965 accession
Allen, Henry Tureman, 1859-1930.
1903: Feb. 14, Sept. 17, Dec. 16 1904: May 6, May 11, May 28, Oct. 12, Oct. 23 1905: June 3, June 9, June 19, Oct. 14, Nov. 24, Dec. 14, Dec. 15 1906: Jan. 12 1907: Jan. 23, Mar. 23, Sept. 11 1908: Jan. 21, Dec. 19, Dec. 24 1909: Feb. 26, Mar. 8, May 6, May 17, Dec. 23 1910: Feb. 5, Feb. 9, Mar. 1, Mar. 8, Oct. 22 1911: April 12, Aug. 2 1912: Jan. 9, Feb. 16, Feb. 29 1913: Jan. 24, Mar. 1, Mar. 10, Apr. 16, May 24
Bell, James Franklin, 1856-1919.
1902: July 24, Oct. 16 1907: Sept. 5 1911: Oct. 23
Burrows, Julius Caesar, 1837-1915.
1904: Feb. 15, Apr. 15, May 5, July 6 1907: Jan. 14 1909: June 3
Carpenter, Frank W.
1909: Apr. 19, Sept. 3 1911: Nov 27
Forbes, William Cameron, 1870-1959.
1905: June 7, June 16 1906: Aug 3 1907: July 6 1909: Apr. 21, July 29, Sept. 4, Dec. 7, Dec. 23, Dec. 28, Dec. 29 1910: Aug. 4 1911: Aug. 5 1913: Apr. 4
Funston, Frederick, 1865-1917.
1912: Nov. 7, Nov. (?)
Gilbert, Newton Whiting, 1862-1939.
1907: May 13 1908: Jan. 23 1909: Apr. 21, June 13, July 3 1910: May 11 1911: Aug. 3 1912: Jan. 28, May 16, Oct. 14 1913: Mar. 25
Harbord, James Guthrie, 1866-1947.
1905: Oct. 27, Oct. 31, Nov. 10, Nov. 22, Dec. 3, Dec. 16, Dec. 25, Dec. 26 1906: Jan. 2, Jan. 11, Jan. 16, Jan. 20, Jan. 22, Jan. 23, Jan. 29, Feb. 1, Feb. 6, Feb. 7, Feb. 10-11, Feb. 19, Feb. 26, Feb. 27, Mar. 3, Mar. 7, Mar. 9, Mar. 10, Mar. 13, Mar. 26, Mar. 28, Apr. 20, Sept. 1, Sept. 27, Oct. 7, Oct. 26 1907: Feb. 18, Mar. 13, Mar. 24, Apr. 3, Apr. 5, Apr. 24, Apr. 29, May 4, May 5, May 7, May 9, June 30, July 10, July 12, July 17, Aug. 4, Aug. 14, Aug. 19, Aug. 21, Aug. 24, Sept. 3, Sept. 4, Nov. 27, Dec. 10 1908: Jan. 10, Jan. 13, Jan. 27, Feb. 7, July 28 1909: Feb. 12, Apr. 2, Apr. 4, Apr. 7, May 6, May 28, June 6, June 13, June 21, July 5, July 7, July 19, July 22, July 30, Aug. 6, Aug. 17, Sept. 1, Sept. 7, Sept. 9, Sept. 14, Oct. 5, Oct. 13, Oct. 22, Oct. 27, Oct. 30, Nov. 7, Nov. 13 1910: Jan. 7, Feb. 18, Mar. 21, Apr. 11, May 30, Dec. 16 1911: Mar. 5, Mar. 7, May 5, May 24, June 14, Oct. 28, 1911, Dec. 14 1913: Mar. 10, May 18
Hersey, Mark Leslie, 1863-1934
1906: Oct. 4, Oct. 6 1907: June 21 1909: Mar. 23, May 4, May 6, June 6, July 2, Aug. 6 1910: Mar. 10, Mar. 17, Sept. 29, Oct. 18, Oct. 31, Nov. 10, Nov. 21, Dec. 6, Dec. 7 1911: May 9, July 11, Aug. 7, Aug. 10, Sept. 15, Oct. 6, Oct. 10, Oct. 17, Nov. 10, Nov. 18, Dec. 11, Dec. 12, and undated 1911 1913: Mar. 24, Apr. 1, June 13
Ide, Henry Clay, 1844-1921.
1905: July 6 1906: Feb. 16, Mar. 17, July 20, Aug. 29 1907: Mar. 22, May 27, July 8
Kahn, Julius, 1861-1924.
1912: Nov. 2, Nov. 3 1913: Mar. 7, Apr. 16, Apr. 17
Mills, Albert Leopold, 1854-1916.
1907: July 3 1909: Mar. 9, Mar. 10
Osmena, Sergio, 1878-1961.
1907: July 1, July 5, July 12, Aug. 1, Aug. 2 1908: Dec. 15 1910: Dec. 16
Pershing, John Joseph, 1860-1948.
1907: July 19 1910: Jan. 14, July 17 1911: Jan. 30, Mar. 1, Mar. 29, July 17, July 31 1913: Apr. 1
Quezon, Manuel Luis, 1878-1944.
1906: Jan. 4, Jan. 23, Feb. 21, Feb. 23, Mar. 3, Mar. 5, Mar. 10, Mar. 14, Mar. 27, May 28, June 18, June 19, June 20, Aug. 23, Aug. 31, Dec. 18 1907: Jan. 23, Feb. 8, Feb. 18, Aug. 3 1909: Sept. 14, Nov. 21 1910: Apr. 26, June 30, Sept. 7, Dec. 22, Dec. 23, Dec. 28 1911: Jan. 5, Jan. 25, Feb. 25, Mar. 11, Apr. 12, July 8, Aug. 19, Aug. 29, Oct. 23, Oct. 28, Nov. 1, Nov. 3, Nov. 11, Nov. 25, Dec. 11 1913: Jan. 2, Jan. 25, Mar. 17, Apr. 15, Apr. 17, May 24
Smith, James Francis, 1859-1928.
1909: May 10, July 6
Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.
1908: Nov. 16 1909: Jan. 9, Feb. 13, Mar. 22, Apr. 30, July 22, Sept. 1, Oct. 13, Dec. 22, Dec. 23 1910: Jan. 31, Feb. 9, Mar. 11, Mar. 23, May 12, June 28, Aug. 12, Sept. 6, Sept. 13, Nov. 6, Nov. 23, Nov. 28, Dec. 6 1911: May 25 1912: May 14, Nov. 2, Nov. 7, Dec. 30 1913: Jan. 20, Feb. 3, Feb. 4, Feb. 21, Mar. 6, Apr. 2, Apr. 11, Apr. 18
Selective index to correspondents in 1994 accession
Bigelow, Poultney, 1855-1954.
1921: Nov. 8
Bliss, Tasker Howard, 1853-1930.
1919: Sept. 5
Bumpus, Hermon Carey, 1862-1943.
1906: Jan. 5, Jan. 31, Feb. 20, Mar. 15.
Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.
1922: June 7.
Forbes, William Cameron, 1870-1959.
1907: July 6 1912: June 15 1915: Dec. 17 1917: May 22
Harbord, James Guthrie, 1866-1947.
1921: Mar. 1, Mar. 2, Mar. 6 1924: June 24
Ide, Henry Clay, 1844-1921.
1907: May 27
McIntyre, Frank, 1865-1944.
1912: July 12 1913: Mar. 31, May 12, July 3, Aug. 11 1914: Jan. 6 1924: Jan. 3
Pershing, John Joseph, 1860-1948.
1918: Nov. 29 1919: Mar. 28, Oct. 14 1923: June 29, Dec. 20
Polk, Frank Lyon, 1871-1943.
1919: Oct. 17, Nov. 4, Nov. 15
Quezon, Manuel Luis, 1878-1944.
See separate folder
Rivers, William Cannon, 1866-1943.
See separate folder
Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.
1917: June 21, June 28, July 20, Nov. 28
Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958.
See separate folder
Taft, William Howard, 1857-1930.
1903: Jan. 23 1908: July 31, Aug. 28 1911: May 13, Oct. 3
Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.
1912: July 13
Wickersham, George Woodward, 1858-1936.
1918: Mar. 8
Wright, Luke E., 1846-1922.
1902 throughout 1921: Apr. 28 1923: Feb. 8, June 12, June 13, Dec. 28
Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.
See separate folder
Selective index to correspondents in 2005 accession
Aguinaldo, Emilio, 1869-1964.
1911: Apr. 8
Ola, Simeon, 1865-
1905: Nov. 12 1907: Mar. 12
Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.
1911: Aug. 3, Nov. 7, Dec. 4
Wright, Luke E., 1846-1922.
1907: Jan. 19, May 13 1908: Oct. 26 1909: Jan. 22